<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Pelican DEMO</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/</id><updated>2013-03-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>'Coding Dojo: Lua with LÖVE'</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/coding-dojo-lua-with-love.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>me</name></author><id>tag:soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo,2013-03-02:coding-dojo-lua-with-love.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lua.org/"&gt;Lua&lt;/a&gt; is a lightweight and extensible language that is designed to be embedded for scripting. Which is why it's very popular &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Lua-scripted_video_games"&gt;in game dev&lt;/a&gt;. This language is a good and simple example of how to do a lot when you have a little.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://love2d.org/"&gt;LÖVE&lt;/a&gt; is a spiffy framework for 2D games in Lua. It's cross-platform, performant, completely free, and great for &lt;a href="https://www.love2d.org/wiki/Category:Games"&gt;small games and prototyping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be using LÖVE to animate an abstract scene, complete with music and special effects, in a Coding Dojo format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a feel for both the language and the framework, check out these links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.lua.org/download.html"&gt;Download Lua&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introductory topics in the Lua Tutorial Directory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.love2d.org/wiki/Main_Page"&gt;LÖVE Wiki&lt;/a&gt; (explains how to start and provides a bunch of tutorials)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of what the Coding Dojo events are, just browse past meetups history. The link to Past Meetups is on the left, below our logo; or check out &lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/NetRateu/coding-dojo-applied"&gt;these slides&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dojo"></category><category term="lua"></category></entry><entry><title>'Hackathon: JavaScript with CouchDB'</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/hackathon-javascript-with-couchdb.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>me</name></author><id>tag:soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo,2013-01-19:hackathon-javascript-with-couchdb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CouchDB is a simple tool. Simple tools can be used creatively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have a small task to implement for our entertainment. In the process you'll touch the core concepts of CouchDB, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structured schema-less storage;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Btree-based views to lookup and summarize the data;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transformations: views and lists written in JavaScript;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;REST interface over HTTP;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design documents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic knowledge of JavaScript, HTML, jQuery, and HTTP protocol is required to get most of the event. I also suggest to take a look on CouchDB documentation by reading the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/Technical_Overview"&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/Technical_Overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/Introduction_to_CouchDB_views"&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/Introduction_to_CouchDB_views&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you're still hungry after reading the above, try to grok:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/View_collation"&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/View_collation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/HTTP_view_API"&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/couchdb/HTTP_view_API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bring a laptop.&lt;/strong&gt; The preferred way to code is to work in pairs but solo is fine too. You can even form teams and try social coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of what the Hackathon events are, just browse past meetups history. The link to Past Meetups is on the left, below our logo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackaton"></category></entry><entry><title>Beeralization x03</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/beeralization-x03.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>me</name></author><id>tag:soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo,2012-12-21:beeralization-x03.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We started half a year ago and there are already things to retrospect and improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have vision for next year events, including The Big One. We would love to see cross-community involvment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gladly ask Ryby, Python, Web, Oracle, Microsoft, FP community leaders and participants to join us in this relaxed evening to discuss plans and event calendar for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good bear and snacks at Bon Vivant! Bring your wallet, though :)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="social"></category></entry><entry><title>'Coding Dojo: Haskell'</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/coding-dojo-haskell.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>me</name></author><id>tag:soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo,2012-12-15:coding-dojo-haskell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downoad Haskell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Haskell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll cover a little bit of 1st and 2nd to get you started for the 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously, though, FP is quite often misunderstood or cited out of context as panacea for every programmer's problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll have a small task to challenge in functional-style and time to discuss what are real strengths and weaknesses of Haskell and the tools proposed by the FP movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, allocate some time to get familiar with Haskell. The more you dig into it, the better for the event. To get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://yannesposito.com/Scratch/en/blog/Haskell-the-Hard-Way/"&gt;Learn Haskell Fast and Hard&lt;/a&gt; – a tutorial for the impatient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://learnyouahaskell.com/"&gt;Learn You a Haskell for Great Good!&lt;/a&gt; – a [rather lengthy] book for those, who never tried FP before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the event we'll have two documentation resources at our disposal: a &lt;a href="http://cheatsheet.codeslower.com/CheatSheet.pdf"&gt;cheat sheet&lt;/a&gt; and an API search engine, &lt;a href="http://www.haskell.org/hoogle/"&gt;Hoogle&lt;/a&gt;, opened in a browser tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get an idea of what the Coding Dojo events are, just browse past meetups history. The link to Past Meetups is on the left, below our logo.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dojo"></category><category term="haskell"></category></entry><entry><title>Twitter Bootstrap Hackathon</title><link href="http://soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo/twitter-bootstrap-hackathon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>me</name></author><id>tag:soulne4ny.github.com/pelican-demo,2012-11-17:twitter-bootstrap-hackathon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lets-work-in-pairs workshop to get Twitter Bootstrap based website up and running. We'll start with the very basic stuff - downloading the Bootstrap and, depending on our performance, progressing through HTML/CSS coding to making our site talk to a primitive &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt; backend. I hope we'll touch the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Responsive_web_design"&gt;Responsive Web Design&lt;/a&gt; topic a little bit too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, devote some time to review the &lt;a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/"&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; documentation and refresh your CSS and JavaScript skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone interested in modern, adaptive, responsive website template is invited: designers, web developers, html coders, backend developers. Anyone can do a pretty website nowadays!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="hackaton"></category></entry></feed>